Hadi Lashkari Ghouchani

Software Engineer

@ hi@hadilq.com

hadilg.com

O Toronto, Canada

github.com/hadilq

@hadilq@androiddev.social

in linkedin.com/in/hadilq

Summary

A curious developer with over 17 years of experience in software development, where almost 7 years of his expe rience covers Android development, over 2 years covers teaching algorithms and programming in universities, and over 8 years covers academic and self-employed experiences while he was a student.

An Introvert person who has profound learning and contributing skills. A creative, value-driven developer who enjoys doing math, solving problems and creating scalable, maintainable, testable and efficient apps to make the world a better place to live. He values bayesian mindsets. He pursue reproducible, frictionless, consistent, and

A person whose goal is to surround himself with creative, clever, motivative and happy persons, so he can continuously learn more and more, not just learning, of course. In fact, he has valuable knowledge and sturdy knowledge transfer skills to share it. He knows that working with great minds will unleash his potential to be more

He's interested in decreasing build time, improving productivity of engineers by tooling. With Gradle's unregulated world, who doesn't want a productivity engineer, or a passionate tool maker in reach?

Experience

Software Engineer

at MobileLIVE

🛗 Apr. 2021 - Present

Toronto, Canada

MobileLIVE is a Canadian tech-service provider unifying people, technology, and business to accelerate digital transformation. Over this time, he worked in Bell Canada as a full-time contractor. Bell Canada is subsidiary Bell Aliant provides services in the Atlantic provinces. It provides mobile service through its Bell Mobility (including Virgin Mobile Canada) subsidiary, and television through its Bell Satellite TV and Bell Fibe TV subsidiaries.

Mission:

- Introduced RFCs to make technical decisions and steps to applying on any new idea.
- Adding value by teaching and discussing SOLID principles, and best practices of modularization, feature flags, and monorepo, etc
- Raise and implement the idea of automatically cloning and building all the source code in the multi-repo setup to reduce version conflicts, and improve code visibility for debugging purposes
- Raise the need for Gradle Enterprise and Productivity Engineer in the team, which leads to be the one who setup the Gradle Enterprise in the project to improve the build time, and create the necessary tools.
- $Investigate\ problems\ related\ to\ proxy\ and\ self-signed\ certificates\ in\ VPN\ networks,\ where\ by\ implementing$ a script to install them automatically increased the build count in GE dashboard by 164%
- Implement a Jetpack Compose desktop app, to prepare the configuration for building Bell's project.
- Raise and implement the need for Gradle Converntional Plugins to reduce duplication and errors, and also improve consistency among Gradle configurations and versions of external libraries. Technologies

- Kotlin Coroutines / Mockk, Mockito, jUnit, etc.
- Agile, Sprint, Lane based branching strategy, CI/CD
- Atlassian Jira, Atlassian Confluence, Gitlab, Jenkins, Slack, Branch.io, inVision, Dynatrace, etc.

Staff Android Developer

m Oct. 2020 - Mar. 2021

Barcelona, Spain

iFood is an ambitious project to build an entire food delivery ecosystem for all around the world. Currently, it's the biggest food delivery in Brazil, Colombia and Mexico, with 50+ million apps installed on Android devices alone. The Android project is highly modularized to make it possible for 50+ developers working on it fast.

Mission:

- Propose and implement composite build to handle dependency management in Gradle. It decreased the rebuild time while updating a library from more than 13 min to less than a minute
- Implement Android side of metadata project. Its purpose is gathering all information of our highly modularized Android/iOS projects in a dashboard along backend information
- Propose and apply a concept to move out the legacy code from the root module. It decreased the rebuild time of freed up modules by 55%
- · Detect many ANRs and resolved them by applying architectural principles.
- · Wrap up external libraries to better handling panic situations

Technologies

- Dagger 2, Room, Kotlin Coroutines, Moshi, WorkManager / Mockk, Robolectric, jUnit, etc.
- Agile, Sprint, Github Flow, CI/CD, Gradle Enterprise
- Atlassian Jira, Atlassian Confluence, Github, Jenkins, Slack, Databricks, Firebase, Bugsnag, Logzio, etc.

Senior Android Developer at Letgo

m Oct. 2019 - Mar. 2021

Barcelona, Spain

Letgo is the biggest classified marketplace in Turkey with 15+ million apps installed on Android devices

Mission:

- Improve the performance of loading feeds by at least a minute
- · Fix multiple Memory leaks
- . Known as "The man who broke the escape room" to emphasize his ability to think out of the box
- Dagger 2, RxJava 2, Room / Mockito, Espresso, Robolectric, Jacoco, Ktlint, Fastlane, etc.
- Agile, Sprint, Github Flow, CI/CD, Dynamic Feature Module Delivery
- · Atlassian Jira, Atlassian Confluence, Github, Jenkins, Slack, Figma, New Relic, Firebase, Amplitude, etc.

Lead Android Developer

at Sheypoor

🛗 Jan. 2018 - Jan. 2019

O Tehran, Iran

Sheypoor is one of two lead classified marketplaces in Iran with 1.5+ million users per day, 13+ million

Missions:

- Increase the number of users per day from 0.5+ million to 1.5+ million in a year. Technologies
- Dagger 2, RxJava 2, Butter Knife, Greendao / Mockito, Espresso, Jacoco, etc.

• Agile, Kanban, Git Flow, CI/CD / Pivotal Tracker, Github, Jenkins, Slack, Zeplin, etc. Senior Android Developer

m Sep. 2015 - Des. 2017

Tehran, Iran

Myket is one of two lead app stores in Iran with over 8+ million users. TL;DR Mission: Starting TDD and installing Jenking's pipeline to handle CI/CD.

Java and C# developer

at Soha System

mar. 2015 - Aug. 2015

Tehran, Iran

SOHA is formed to focus on solutions based on smart cards. TL;DR Mission: Implementing Android and

Article / Repository

- 2021 ProAndroidDev post: Happy Railway. An improvement for Railway Oriented Programming in Kotlin. Q 2021 Library: Happy is a library to auto-generate Kotlin code to make calling APIs more concise.
- 2020 POC: Rust Flutter Reactive is an idea to use Flutter as UI and Rust for the main project.
- 2020 Make Log4k Multiplatform: Simple logging library for Android, iOS, Mac, etc. M 2020 ProAndroidDev post: A/B Testing Myths
- 2020 Sample App: Provide a full implementation for a No-Framework Dependency Injection in Kotlin \bigcirc 2020 Contributing on Λ rrow Library: Λ rrow is a library for Typed Functional Programming in Kotlin \bigcirc 2020 Library: A Kotlin compiler plugin that generates trackable method
- 1 2020 Medium post: Save State By Using RxJava or Kotlin Flow 2020 Medium post: RxJava instead of LiveData in MVVM
- 2020 Library: A glue between the lifecycle of LifecycleOwner in Android and upstreams in RxJava 🔾 2020 Library: A glue between the lifecycle of LifecycleOwner in Android and Kotlin Coroutines
- 🔿 2019 Sample App: Movie Challenge
- 🔾 2019 Math Library: Modularized, mathematical and multiplatform Kotlin library

- 2018 Sample App: Clean Architecture + RMVVM
- ☑ 2018 ProAndroidDev post: Loading entities from database and server API by using RxJava ☑ 2018 ProAndroidDev post: LiveData with single events 2018 LiveEvent library: It's useful to propagate single event to View

Education

Payame Noor University

Sharif University Of Technology

B.Sc

M.Sc

in Physics in Physics

m Jul. 2007

• Tehran, Iran Mashhad, Iran

Tools / Skills

Android

Partially Open Source Mobile Lifecycles/LiveData/Navigation/Paging/ViewModel Multidex/Test/Data Binding/WorkManager/Room Android Architecture Components/JetPack Anvil/Dagger 2/RxJava 2/Retrofit 2/.. Kotlin Multiplatform/Kotlin Coroutines Kotlin Compiler Plugin/KSP/. Compose/Data Binding/View Binding/...

Summary of why he's interested It's partially open source OS Generally interested on Mobile Technologies.

Flutter

StatelessWidget/StatefulWidget StreamController/Isolates

Summary of why he's interested: Generally interested on all cross-platform and multi-platform solutions.

Rust

tonic/prost/openssl/tokio/flatbuffers/thrift Rc/Arc/Mutex

Summary of why he's interested: Rust's type system is what you need for scale-up. Borrow Checker restrictly stops any memory leaks. Bevy, and Dioxus frameworks look like good candidates for cross-platform solutions.

Nix

NixOS/Nix Darwin mkDrivation/mkShell

Summary of why he's interested: Reproducibility is the key to productivity.

Architecture

Clean Architecture/Hexagonal Architecture Unidirectional data flow Architecture MVVM/MVI/MVP/RMVVM

Principle

Clean Code/SOLID Object Oriented Programming Functional Programming Stable Dependencies Principle Stable Abstractions Principle

Design Pattern Factory/Builder/Singleton/...

Android test library

Adapter/Facade/Proxy/Visitor/Delegate/... Strategy/Chain of responsibility/...

JUnit/Mockito/Espresso/Jacoco/...

Build Tool Gradle/Cargo/Sbt/Maven/Ant/Make/...

Command Line Tool grep/sed/netstat/awk/docker/..

Development Tool

adb/sdkmanager/avdmanager/...

Pivotal Tracker/Jira/Jenkins/Travis/CircleCi/...

Programing Language Java/Kotlin/Rust/Scala/Haskell/Python Groovy/Dart/Javascript/Ruby...

Operating System

Linux(Nix OS/Fedora/Ubuntu/Debian), OS X

Special Honor

- 2020 Had an offer from MobileLIVE, Toronto, Canada 2020 Had an offer from iFood, Remote
- 2019 Had an offer from Kik, Kitechener, Canada 2019 Had an offer from Letgo, Barcelona, Spain
- 2019 Had an offer from CRITICAL Techworks, BMW, Porto, Portugal 2019 Had an offer from The Next Big Thing, Berlin,
 - Germany
 2018 Received result-oriented badge in Sheypoor
 - 2007 Ranked 44th among more than five thousand participants in the National Graduate Entrance Exam in

Language

English: Advance Farsi: Native

The source of this resume is in github Built on September 13, 2023